{"data":[{"question":"Your fingers are very brown. You _____ (smoke) too much.","a":"has been smoking","b":"have been smoking","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when there is a connection with now. The action in the past and has a result now\n- You have been smoking....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"Her phone _____ (ring) for ten minutes. I wonder why she doesn't answer it.","a":"has been ringing","b":"have been ringing","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(for ten minutes)\n- Her phone has been ringing.....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"The trial _____ (go) on for a long time. I wonder what the verdict will be.","a":"has been going","b":"have been going","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(for a long time)\n- The trial has been going.......","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"You usually know when someone _____ (eat) garlic.","a":"has been eating","b":"have been eating","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when there is an action happened in the past, has results now and still happening now","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"I _____ (bathe). That's why my hair is all wet.","a":"has been bathing","b":"have been bathing","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when something has happened, has a result now, and is still happening now.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"He _____ (speak) for an hour now. I expect he'll soon be finished.","a":"has been speaking","b":"have been speaking","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for an hour now)\n- He has been speaking...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"Ever since he came to us that man _____ (try) to make trouble.","a":"has been trying","b":"have been trying","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when someone keeps doing something that's annoying.\n- That's men has been trying...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"The radio _____ (play) since 7 a.m. I wish someone would turn it off.","a":"has been playing","b":"have been playing","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (since 7a.m)\n- The radio has been playing....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"How long you _____ (drive)?\nI _____ (drive) for ten years.","a":"has you been driving\/has been driving","b":"have you been driving\/have been driving","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for ten years)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"},{"question":"Someone _____ (use) my bicycle. The chain's fallen off.","a":"has been using","b":"have been using","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when something has happened and there is a connection with now","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"7"}]}